jodia todas para gracias gracias para
esta comida important are the
participants to some horizontal position
usually musical legacy must remain
computer science oxy what's your life is
if you seduced our key or here the boys
the practice Panama is somewhere sir if
you allow me I will continue in English
it's a little bit easier that's anger
that you just say I do admire them to
hear this morning it speaks to you as a
person it speaks to you as a
professional played speaks to you as a
personal care I think there is
tremendous it's a tribute to you we open
look at the planet as you feels a little
different planets but we have never
liked that make a common passion for
Carlos and George you have invited us to
discuss get this morning the social
contract it's an interesting question do
we owe you one well the first assumption
is if you're more open and i think if
you look at the state of our global
discourse as a community of nations but
also societies with one another then I
think the answer to this first question
has to be yes I think the social
contract or contracts you would even say
I rather robin or operating them if you
go back take me to go to I think the
notion that you use the exercise which
is the mega contract that will be called
it the mega contrary of the planet
associated multilateralism and the UN
then clearly we had after the second or
a new social contract now contract have
sometimes the reality that not everybody
who is affected by the necessary science
and but we had a whole second world wars
on the contract in the world which found
its expression of the charter of the
United Nations in the aspiration of the
peoples of the world to find a better
way to deal the differences because
differences are reality and I think this
is one of the things you must always
accept we will never be all the same
whether you describe in economic reality
or in cultural identity or vision and
social aspiration but that's social
contract last remaining 20 30 years and
lodging in the 60s and even into the 70s
the United Nations became a vehicle for
progressive development is social and
political policy making it grow
operations into a different discourse
with one another endless within their
own societies it introduced not only the
notion of human rights for goes to the
right of the government
fundamental concepts that have shaped
not only the mega contract level but
also the national level but that
contract began to enroll already city
this through the Cold War and the United
Nations became dr. Seter the center
where we search for common answers but
the place will be awful play of the
differences that exist if he blocks
within nations that whole era internet
the 99 to around in the 1980s and 1990s
summit I think could be described as a
new social contract that the world
reached in 92 it was a social contract
that expresses of the notion sustainable
development now some view that as a
civilizational challenge others define
it in the form of common but
differentiated responsibilities in there
you see in a contract as many closest
and how do you reconcile the vision of
those who look to the leaders of the
world to challenge the inability to
recognize and act on planetary realities
as our colleague dr. Pachauri and the
IPCC constantly our reminder of what
haps one of the best and eidos where
science challenges political in action
even if it is
of assessments that takes time but I
think the story of climate change and
science and politics on the planet is a
very interesting case that your heart
this social contract works of his not
work 11-8 of the office we meet here in
2012 and the social contract of
sustainable development 1992 is breaking
out if I'm already broken I saw uncommon
for yesterday the paper and if it's
enough it was by a person who spent a
lot of his time arguing that we should
be about reaffirming the agreement of 92
native who are then criticized that
there are 59 citations of reformation in
the outcome document of 2012 it is that
really enough and here you see also
there is a oscillation on uncertainty of
what we actually try to re trying to
protect the contract of 92 or are we
trying to all the new contract or do we
have to make a completely new contract
in this form and I think this is where
it gets interesting the person the
question is the contract was made in
nineteen forty
the 1950s the contract that was
negotiated in 1992 here was between
poetry for water who was at a table and
whatever you might save on a 92 and its
enormous power of of guiding us in a
common direction the world is getting a
change in 2012 not only in terms of
motion South in terms of you know
economies of the south and emerging
economies having become bigger in
economies in Europe on the verge of
economic collapse with unemployment
rates for donkeys like fifty percent and
unimaginable realities right now that
were inconceivable to many just a few
years ago at the same time the emergence
also civil society is more than just a
companion to the political
decision-making process but challenging
the foundations of public decision
making and also the fact that the
corporate sector is in one sense at the
center of controversy analysis is also
splitting in two different strategies a
number of corporate leaders here we have
to be
we accepted that their role as Oprah
needed as corporations is no longer to
just pay the taxes and get over their
business regulation practices because
perhaps they recognize that the social
foundations of this contract are
breaking up now you can be sitting on
several apps bad for business well if
it's bad for business it's business
begins to think about how to do things
differently and I again won't decide on
a ton of confidence in Fargo Barboza
fluence of civil terms and we awarded in
the champions of the earth award each
one of those business leaders who goes
beyond just thinking about the business
of today's in the business of business
is sustainable business it may not be
the same agenda is that a three piece or
the movie latest in here but it is still
a part of or let's say the party's in a
part of the social program today you
cannot simply decree a contract top down
anymore in a summit and honest so
attention that we have had to deal with
does it challenged the sovereignty of
the state
I'm sure it does but does it challenge
perhaps the emergence of past clients
that need to simply get together and
decide what is good for their peoples
suddenly and I think that tension
pervaiz real 2012 is civil society
organizing a summative parallel and
almost in the different separation from
the summit that is naked lady feel this
must tell us something this is wrong in
the way we view either the opportunity
or the nature of this contract but also
what is our contract about today I
believe that we are having the wrong
conversations in these summits because
they're missing the point of where
societies are searching for common
pathways a forward if you go back to at
the date card sustainable development
that says we want for the SS if I'm will
be waterborne environment there's some
more women and less winning only one
World public ownership and less market
if you want less capitalism and more
socialism or it is motherhood and the
polymeric approach to development versus
the American and US approach of
corporate capitalism these are the
calamities of our conversation today but
they don't offer us necessarily a way I
wish to connect the threads of different
interests in a way that allows a social
contract management I went to the summit
of the peoples in order to have a
conversation about the green economy and
the concerns in the fields that have
been articulated by some massage
movements with our concert and to me it
is fascinating how different an
association we have when we talk about a
sponsor to me Rio 2012 they deliver a
progressive step in this is false
because I knew it is critical that the
environmental sustainability dimension
is no longer kept in a parallel track
but enters the center stage of the
development dispose which is dominated
by economic markets so if the green tea
company comes out of here as a whole
concept around you have to work
environmentalism some of this place is
social and developmental aspirations
it's while addressing something that
went wrong after view recently had three
dimensions to sustain the penguin or
what happened in the 500 is was the same
atom of trade-offs being the equation I
mean thought my time is absolutely
simply conclude by saying two things
I've been trying to cook for an image to
describe the outcome document yet when I
was taking out on social contract
clearly here in Rio in 2012 the world is
unable to sign a new social contract and
I think unreal derivative we all know
that this is not our contract among the
nations of the world amongst the seven
billion people with all the differences
accounted for on having achieved a set
of common objectives and aspirations
that are transformational I disagree
with those who say this document is
devoid of content
wrong if you look at this document there
is a lot in that document but when you
change the trajectory sustainable
development in the sense of a social
contract no one analogy that alternative
is that overcome book you know the
cookbook you have the recipe you have
the contents and you have the
instructions if you look at the album
operators in all of Africa cookbook make
ingredients are there in some place it
even has the quantities eating is in
some places a cooking time but you'd
only have a whole recipe there you also
have not in a sense a whole menu regular
but in the cookbook that is not fully
mentioned there is still a lot of
information in there for maybe there is
enough to work with it in order to
continue building foundations for a new
social contract and another one this
perhaps more negatively major that is I
think the challenge for Marco naturalism
today it is not your chess board on
which the figures and the rules have
been defined and if I move that you make
on his chest for today produces another
tactical move from the other side that
was not be intent where the chest full
of the United Nations Charter was
written almost 60 years ago and I think
we are at a point where the dynamics of
multilateral negotiations are almost in
every three take off negotiations but
every step is defined
the other one and we have lost sight of
what the original idea of the chest what
was the first ever game together to
arrive not necessary the logic of chess
where one meets the evidence but that we
somehow elevate the prospect for one to
be able to work together believe in your
chessboard and we are desperately
looking for how that